<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xampp on Live Life D̶a̶n̶g̶e̶r̶o̶u̶s̶Curiously</title>
    <link>https://www.riospace.web.id/tags/xampp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xampp on Live Life D̶a̶n̶g̶e̶r̶o̶u̶s̶Curiously</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 07:28:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.riospace.web.id/tags/xampp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Amazon Web Service MySQL Database Using PhpMyAdmin</title>
      <link>https://www.riospace.web.id/accessing-amazon-web-service-mysql-database-using-phpmyadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 07:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.riospace.web.id/accessing-amazon-web-service-mysql-database-using-phpmyadmin/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Service currently offers one-year-free trial of their services and I am experimenting with their database service. I set up a MySQL server database. However, after the service was ready, I found out that, AWS doesn”t provide GUI to access the database. I always use phpMyAdmin to manage MySQL database because it is easy and thinking whether I could use phpMyAdmin to manage my AWS database or not. After a quick research on the Internet, I found out that it is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XAMPP for Linux Installation</title>
      <link>https://www.riospace.web.id/xampp-for-linux-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 23:34:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.riospace.web.id/xampp-for-linux-installation/</guid>
      <description>XAMPP, an abbreviation for X (Linux or Windows or Mac OS X or Solaris), Apache, MySQL, PHP, Perl, is an application composed of a web service (Apache), a database server (MySQL) and a FTP server (ProFTPD) which is intended for development environment. As mentioned above, XAMPP runs both in Windows and UNIX based operating systems.
This chance I will explain how to install XAMPP on Linux operating systems. Here are the specifications I use in this tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>