<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on Live Kaizen life</title>
    <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/categories/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on Live Kaizen life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 07:28:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.riospace.web.id/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Amazon Web Service MySQL Database Using PhpMyAdmin</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/accessing-amazon-web-service-mysql-database-using-phpmyadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 07:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/accessing-amazon-web-service-mysql-database-using-phpmyadmin/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Service currently offers one-year-free trial of their services and I am experimenting with their database service. I set up a MySQL server database. However, after the service was ready, I found out that, AWS doesn”t provide GUI to access the database. I always use phpMyAdmin to manage MySQL database because it is easy and thinking whether I could use phpMyAdmin to manage my AWS database or not. After a quick research on the Internet, I found out that it is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QAM Modulation Technique Concept Challenges and Solutions</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/qam-modulation-technique-concept-challenges-and-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 14:33:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/qam-modulation-technique-concept-challenges-and-solutions/</guid>
      <description>The new 802.11ac standard from IEEE, is currently penetrating wireless network markets with its new features and technology. Watson (2013), Public Marketing of Meru Networks, claims the 802.11ac standard will be able to provide a maximum client data rate per radio of 1.3 Gbps. How does it manage to achieve those higher bandwidths compared to the last standard? One part of this technology that makes it possible is the complex modulation technique that 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Stargazing Report</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-stargazing-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:29:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-stargazing-report/</guid>
      <description>Well, actually I stargazed before, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t do that to really observe stars and constellations. This time was my first time stargazing as a beginner in Astronomy (learning Astronomy is part of my new year resolutions). It was Monday Night, January the 6th of 2014. I started to stargaze around EST 9.00 pm until 10.00 pm. It was cold in Syracuse since the temperature was -12 degree of Celsius, and the wind, that made the weather colder, blew with the speed of 50 kph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berjebraw Forefathers Chord</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/berjebraw-forefathers-chord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 12:46:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/berjebraw-forefathers-chord/</guid>
      <description> This song was written by Petra G Michael a.k.a Berjebraw. I got to listen to the song yesterday and decided to write the chord. The first time I heard this sing song. I felt like my soul was shaken. Here is the song and the chord
Tuning: Standard EADGBe LEGEND E C# A B F# G# Eb e|----0----0----0----0----0----0----0----| B|----0----0----0----0----0----0----0----| G|----9----6----2----4----4----4----9----| D|----9----6----2----4----4----6----9----| A|----7----4----0----2----4----6----6----| E|------------------------2----0---------| Intro : E E Eb E Look at what the forefathers left for us Eb E Can you feel the spirit moving accordingly Eb One thing I realize about this day C# B Oh, have we learned a thing or two A B From what our forefathers left E C# Have we learned, have we learned F# E Have we learned, have we learned from our forefathers E C# Have we changed, have we changed F# G# A Have we learned, have we learned from the past E F# Yesterday was that you learned A Tomorrow is that for us to dream E And today is that for us to live our life E F# To change for the better, to change for the better A To change for the better, to change for the better E To change for the better &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; E C# have we learned, have we learned F# E have we learned, have we learned from our forefathers E C# have we changed, have we changed F# G# A have we learned, have we learned, have we Learned F# G# A have we learneeeeeeeed, from our forefathers E a thing or two</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pie a Professor</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/pie-a-professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 12:40:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/pie-a-professor/</guid>
      <description>Today, I saw a strange event in my school. Staffs in iSchool Syracuse University were raising money to be donated for United Way. What they did was providing a booth were people can throw pie to iSchool’s professors face. The price is $5 for student and $10 for faculty, but if you only have $3, they&amp;rsquo;ll take it anyway. I was also offered to throw pie on professor face, but I refused it is not because I didn’t have money, but I think that is not appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Biking in Syracuse</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/mountain-biking-in-syracuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 12:26:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/mountain-biking-in-syracuse/</guid>
      <description>Today I went for Mountain Biking trip which is organized by SUOC. I&amp;rsquo;ve done mountain biking when I was in Indonesia almost every weekend. At first I was wondering where can I have good trails for mountain biking in Syracuse. The area is located near Syracuse University south campus. To give you better sense of direction, look at the map below.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t have a decent bike for mountain biking and never go for mountain biking with complete equipment but this time was different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canyoneering in Bear Swamp Creek</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/canyoneering-in-bear-swamp-creek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 07:06:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/canyoneering-in-bear-swamp-creek/</guid>
      <description>I just got home from my first canyoneering trip in my life. Thanks for Syracuse University Outing Club (SUOC) leaders who took me to this trip, here is the story. At first, we set off from SUOC Equipment room (E-room) at 10 am. There were seven people on this trip. Two leaders (Nate and Maggie) and five members (Nick, Megan, John, Sean and me). We went to Bear Swamp Creek in Cayuga County, New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First US&#39;s Family Home Visit</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-uss-family-home-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 06:26:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-uss-family-home-visit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, (4th of August 2013) we went on home visit. We were lucky to have Sue as our host family. Sue&amp;rsquo;s house is quite far from St. John&amp;rsquo;s University since it is located in Ringwood, New Jersey. We took a bus from New York Port Authority Bus Terminal (PABT) to Ringwood. I really enjoy our trip since along the road I saw beautiful trees. Unfortunately, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of trees was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling New Interface in Ubuntu Server</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/enabling-new-interface-in-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 05:59:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/enabling-new-interface-in-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, I replaced one of my network interfaces in my computer. I changed the old one, which is Fast Ethernet type, with the new one, which is Gigabit type. I was working in my Ubuntu server 11.04. When I finished replacing the interface. I turned my computer on to see will it work. I found that the new interface didn”t work. When I plugged the cable in, the LED indicator simply didn”t light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XAMPP for Linux Installation</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/xampp-for-linux-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 23:34:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/xampp-for-linux-installation/</guid>
      <description>XAMPP, an abbreviation for X (Linux or Windows or Mac OS X or Solaris), Apache, MySQL, PHP, Perl, is an application composed of a web service (Apache), a database server (MySQL) and a FTP server (ProFTPD) which is intended for development environment. As mentioned above, XAMPP runs both in Windows and UNIX based operating systems.
This chance I will explain how to install XAMPP on Linux operating systems. Here are the specifications I use in this tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>