<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forefathers on Live Kaizen life</title>
    <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/tags/forefathers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forefathers on Live Kaizen life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 12:46:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.riospace.web.id/tags/forefathers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Berjebraw Forefathers Chord</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/berjebraw-forefathers-chord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 12:46:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/berjebraw-forefathers-chord/</guid>
      <description> This song was written by Petra G Michael a.k.a Berjebraw. I got to listen to the song yesterday and decided to write the chord. The first time I heard this sing song. I felt like my soul was shaken. Here is the song and the chord
Tuning: Standard EADGBe LEGEND E C# A B F# G# Eb e|----0----0----0----0----0----0----0----| B|----0----0----0----0----0----0----0----| G|----9----6----2----4----4----4----9----| D|----9----6----2----4----4----6----9----| A|----7----4----0----2----4----6----6----| E|------------------------2----0---------| Intro : E E Eb E Look at what the forefathers left for us Eb E Can you feel the spirit moving accordingly Eb One thing I realize about this day C# B Oh, have we learned a thing or two A B From what our forefathers left E C# Have we learned, have we learned F# E Have we learned, have we learned from our forefathers E C# Have we changed, have we changed F# G# A Have we learned, have we learned from the past E F# Yesterday was that you learned A Tomorrow is that for us to dream E And today is that for us to live our life E F# To change for the better, to change for the better A To change for the better, to change for the better E To change for the better &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; E C# have we learned, have we learned F# E have we learned, have we learned from our forefathers E C# have we changed, have we changed F# G# A have we learned, have we learned, have we Learned F# G# A have we learneeeeeeeed, from our forefathers E a thing or two</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>