<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Live Kaizen life</title>
    <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Live Kaizen life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 19:06:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.riospace.web.id/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IDN Networking Competition 2017 Mikrotik Bridging Challenge Solution Verification</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/idn-networking-competition-2017-mikrotik-bridging-challenge-solution-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 19:06:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/idn-networking-competition-2017-mikrotik-bridging-challenge-solution-verification/</guid>
      <description>Postingan kali ini adalah lanjutan dari postingan IDN Networking Competition 2017: Mikrotik Bridging Challenge Solution, pastikan kamu telah membaca postingan tersebut, kalau tidak saya jamin pasti akan sedikit bingung. Simulasi yang akan saya paparkan menggunakan teknologi sebagai berikut:
 GNS3 versi 1.5.2 on Windows (64-bit) with Python 3.5.1 Qt 5.6.0 Qemu-2.4.0 running on Local Windows (64-bit) Mikrotik CHR 6.40.1  Topologi yang saya gunakan adalah sebagai berikut:
Pertama yang akan kita lakukan adalah verifikasi dari konektifitas dari tiap lantai (table of content ada di samping kanan)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mengurutkan Interface Pada Virtualisasi Router Mikrotik Di Qemu</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/mengurutkan-interface-pada-virtualisasi-router-mikrotik-di-qemu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 18:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/mengurutkan-interface-pada-virtualisasi-router-mikrotik-di-qemu/</guid>
      <description>Pastinya kita semua pernah mengalami pada saat sedang konsennya konfig mikrotik dan telah selesai dan yakin 100% konfig kita benar, lalu saat kita coba ping &amp;hellip; . . gagal. destination host unreachable. Mungkin salah satu penyebabnya adalah interface yang kita gunakan adalah bukan interface yang benar. Saya sering mengalami hal ini saat menggunakan GNS3 dengan, bisa dibilang hampir semua virtualisasi (VirtualBox dan Qemu) kecuali VMware. Cara yang mudah untuk melakukan pemeriksaan, bisa kita lihat dari MAC address interface melalui command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik Bridging Challenge Solution</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/mikrotik-bridging-challenge-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 16:03:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/mikrotik-bridging-challenge-solution/</guid>
      <description>infoSebelum kamu melakukan copy paste konfigurasi yang akan saya paparkan dalam postingan ini, pastikan penamaan interface pada virtualisai router yang kamu gunakan sudah benar. Kamu bisa ikuti tutorial Mengurutkan Interface pada Virtualisasi Router Mikrotik di Qemu untuk memastikannya
Pada post kali ini saya berusaha memaparkan pendekatan yang saya gunakan untuk menyelesaikan soal bridging pada kompetisi IDN networking 2017 untuk materi superlab Mikrotik, dimana soal dapat dapat di unduh pada link berikut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Amazon Web Service MySQL Database Using PhpMyAdmin</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/accessing-amazon-web-service-mysql-database-using-phpmyadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 07:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/accessing-amazon-web-service-mysql-database-using-phpmyadmin/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Service currently offers one-year-free trial of their services and I am experimenting with their database service. I set up a MySQL server database. However, after the service was ready, I found out that, AWS doesn”t provide GUI to access the database. I always use phpMyAdmin to manage MySQL database because it is easy and thinking whether I could use phpMyAdmin to manage my AWS database or not. After a quick research on the Internet, I found out that it is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QAM Modulation Technique Concept Challenges and Solutions</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/qam-modulation-technique-concept-challenges-and-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 14:33:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/qam-modulation-technique-concept-challenges-and-solutions/</guid>
      <description>The new 802.11ac standard from IEEE, is currently penetrating wireless network markets with its new features and technology. Watson (2013), Public Marketing of Meru Networks, claims the 802.11ac standard will be able to provide a maximum client data rate per radio of 1.3 Gbps. How does it manage to achieve those higher bandwidths compared to the last standard? One part of this technology that makes it possible is the complex modulation technique that 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Stargazing Report</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-stargazing-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:29:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-stargazing-report/</guid>
      <description>Well, actually I stargazed before, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t do that to really observe stars and constellations. This time was my first time stargazing as a beginner in Astronomy (learning Astronomy is part of my new year resolutions). It was Monday Night, January the 6th of 2014. I started to stargaze around EST 9.00 pm until 10.00 pm. It was cold in Syracuse since the temperature was -12 degree of Celsius, and the wind, that made the weather colder, blew with the speed of 50 kph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berjebraw Forefathers Chord</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/berjebraw-forefathers-chord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 12:46:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/berjebraw-forefathers-chord/</guid>
      <description> This song was written by Petra G Michael a.k.a Berjebraw. I got to listen to the song yesterday and decided to write the chord. The first time I heard this sing song. I felt like my soul was shaken. Here is the song and the chord
Tuning: Standard EADGBe LEGEND E C# A B F# G# Eb e|----0----0----0----0----0----0----0----| B|----0----0----0----0----0----0----0----| G|----9----6----2----4----4----4----9----| D|----9----6----2----4----4----6----9----| A|----7----4----0----2----4----6----6----| E|------------------------2----0---------| Intro : E E Eb E Look at what the forefathers left for us Eb E Can you feel the spirit moving accordingly Eb One thing I realize about this day C# B Oh, have we learned a thing or two A B From what our forefathers left E C# Have we learned, have we learned F# E Have we learned, have we learned from our forefathers E C# Have we changed, have we changed F# G# A Have we learned, have we learned from the past E F# Yesterday was that you learned A Tomorrow is that for us to dream E And today is that for us to live our life E F# To change for the better, to change for the better A To change for the better, to change for the better E To change for the better &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; E C# have we learned, have we learned F# E have we learned, have we learned from our forefathers E C# have we changed, have we changed F# G# A have we learned, have we learned, have we Learned F# G# A have we learneeeeeeeed, from our forefathers E a thing or two</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pie a Professor</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/pie-a-professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 12:40:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/pie-a-professor/</guid>
      <description>Today, I saw a strange event in my school. Staffs in iSchool Syracuse University were raising money to be donated for United Way. What they did was providing a booth were people can throw pie to iSchool’s professors face. The price is $5 for student and $10 for faculty, but if you only have $3, they&amp;rsquo;ll take it anyway. I was also offered to throw pie on professor face, but I refused it is not because I didn’t have money, but I think that is not appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Biking in Syracuse</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/mountain-biking-in-syracuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 12:26:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/mountain-biking-in-syracuse/</guid>
      <description>Today I went for Mountain Biking trip which is organized by SUOC. I&amp;rsquo;ve done mountain biking when I was in Indonesia almost every weekend. At first I was wondering where can I have good trails for mountain biking in Syracuse. The area is located near Syracuse University south campus. To give you better sense of direction, look at the map below.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t have a decent bike for mountain biking and never go for mountain biking with complete equipment but this time was different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canyoneering in Bear Swamp Creek</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/canyoneering-in-bear-swamp-creek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 07:06:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/canyoneering-in-bear-swamp-creek/</guid>
      <description>I just got home from my first canyoneering trip in my life. Thanks for Syracuse University Outing Club (SUOC) leaders who took me to this trip, here is the story. At first, we set off from SUOC Equipment room (E-room) at 10 am. There were seven people on this trip. Two leaders (Nate and Maggie) and five members (Nick, Megan, John, Sean and me). We went to Bear Swamp Creek in Cayuga County, New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First US&#39;s Family Home Visit</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-uss-family-home-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 06:26:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-uss-family-home-visit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, (4th of August 2013) we went on home visit. We were lucky to have Sue as our host family. Sue&amp;rsquo;s house is quite far from St. John&amp;rsquo;s University since it is located in Ringwood, New Jersey. We took a bus from New York Port Authority Bus Terminal (PABT) to Ringwood. I really enjoy our trip since along the road I saw beautiful trees. Unfortunately, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of trees was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakso Moro Seneng Pak Slamet Trenggalek</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/bakso-moro-seneng-pak-slamet-trenggalek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 06:20:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/bakso-moro-seneng-pak-slamet-trenggalek/</guid>
      <description>Jika anda pecinta kuliner dan kebetulan sedang singgah di kota keripik Trenggalek pastikan anda menyempatkan diri mampir dan mencicipi Bakso Moro Seneng Pak Slamet.
Hiruk Pikuk pembeli sudah mulai ramai saat saya datang ke lokasi sekitar jam 10 pagi. Warung bakso yang terletak di Jalan Doktor Setiabudi dekat RSUD Doktor Soedomo Trenggalek ini memang selalu ramai pembeli. Usut punya usut ternyata yang menarik banyaknya pembeli ke warung tersebut adalah ke khas-an yang dimiliki oleh warung bakso tersebut yakni gorengan dan sambal baksonya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalasi Lampp Pada Ubuntu Server</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/instalasi-lampp-pada-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 06:07:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/instalasi-lampp-pada-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description>Ini pengalaman pribadi saya saat menginstal Ubuntu Server pada komputer saya. Komputer tersebut ingin saya jadikan sebagai web server, tentu saja saya akan butuh untuk menginstal OpenSSH dan LAMPP. Ubuntu Server pada dasarnya menyediakan pilihan software yang ingin kita instal pada komputer kita saat kita melakukan instalasi. Yakni pada saat kita sampai pada halaman software selection.
Sialnya. Pada saat itu saya tidak tahu bagaimana cara memilih aplikasi yang ingin saya instal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menambahkan Interface Baru Pada Ubuntu Server</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/menambahkan-interface-baru-pada-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 06:04:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/menambahkan-interface-baru-pada-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description>Ceritanya kemarin malam aku ganti salah satu network interface pada Ubuntu Server-ku (Ubuntu 11.04 Natty Narwhal). Niatnya adalah upgrade dari Fast Ethernet jadi Gigabit Ethernet. Setelah aku ganti, aku turned on komputerku. Alhasil indikator LED pada interface yang baru mati (Normalnya akan nyala saat komputer sedang on dan interface terhubung ke jaringan).
Untuk meyakinkan 100% bahwa interface baru tersebut tidak bekerja. Aku jalankan perintah
user@ubuntu:~$ ifconfig dan hasilnya sesuai dengan prediksi saya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling New Interface in Ubuntu Server</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/enabling-new-interface-in-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 05:59:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/enabling-new-interface-in-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, I replaced one of my network interfaces in my computer. I changed the old one, which is Fast Ethernet type, with the new one, which is Gigabit type. I was working in my Ubuntu server 11.04. When I finished replacing the interface. I turned my computer on to see will it work. I found that the new interface didn”t work. When I plugged the cable in, the LED indicator simply didn”t light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XAMPP for Linux Installation</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/xampp-for-linux-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 23:34:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/xampp-for-linux-installation/</guid>
      <description>XAMPP, an abbreviation for X (Linux or Windows or Mac OS X or Solaris), Apache, MySQL, PHP, Perl, is an application composed of a web service (Apache), a database server (MySQL) and a FTP server (ProFTPD) which is intended for development environment. As mentioned above, XAMPP runs both in Windows and UNIX based operating systems.
This chance I will explain how to install XAMPP on Linux operating systems. Here are the specifications I use in this tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalasi XAMPP pada Sistem Operasi Linux</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/instalasi-xampp-pada-sistem-operasi-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 22:34:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/instalasi-xampp-pada-sistem-operasi-linux/</guid>
      <description>XAMPP, kependekan dari X(Linux atau Windows atau Mac OS X atau Solaris), Apache, MySQL, PHP, Perl, merupakan aplikasi yang terdiri dari webserver (Apache), database server (MySQL) serta FTP server (ProFTPD) yang diperuntukkan untuk lingkungan development. Seperti yang disebutkan diatas XAMPP dapat berjalan pada sistem operasi baik berbasis WINDOWS maupun UNIX.
Pada kesempatan kali ini saya akan menjelaskan cara instalasi XAMPP pada sistem operasi linux. Berikut beberapa spesifikasi yang digunakan.
 Sistem Operasi Ubuntu 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle Square War</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/circle-square-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 15:29:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/circle-square-war/</guid>
      <description>Circle Square War adalah sebuah project pada matakuliah Game Development yang saya ikuti semasa saya kuliah di Teknik Informatika ITS. Game ini merupakan pengembangan dari script yang ditulis oleh Philip Radvan mengenai projectile weapons. Berikut adalah game Circle Square War, dimana game ini adalah modifikasi dari script yang ditulis oleh Philip Radvan tersebut.
 Selamat bermain dan jadilah salah satu high scorer game ini. 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tachymeter</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/tachymeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 15:29:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/tachymeter/</guid>
      <description>watch with tachymeter
Beberapa bulan yang lalu saya beli arloji baru (maklum sudah jadi kebutuhan). Bentuknya hampir mirip sama gambar diatas. Setelah dibeli, saya teliti (Emang waktu mau beli ndak di teliti?), ternyata di arloji ada tulisan tachymeter. ini apaan sih? lalu arti dari angka-angka 300, 240, 200 s/d 60 itu apa? Setelah menggali informasi dari google, akhirnya saya mendapatkan kesimpulan bahwa mostly tachymeter digunakan sebagai alat bantu untuk memperkirakan kecepatan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 12:08:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Setelah lama menghilang dari dunia tulis menulis di blog (sekitar 3 tahun) akhirnya saya bertekad untuk membuat blog lagi. Karena saya yakin menulis adalah kegiatan yang bermanfaat (mesti gak bisa menjelaskan secara mendetail). Saya paling malas kalau di suruh menulis, bikin essay dan sebagainya yang berhubungan dengan tulis menulis, maka dari itu saya memaksa diri saya untuk menulis dengan membuat blog yang berbayar alias gak gratis. Supaya saya tambah semangat saat menulis (padahal alasannya sayang kalau ndak diisi soalnya terlanjur dibayar).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>