<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Live Kaizen life</title>
    <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Live Kaizen life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 12:26:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.riospace.web.id/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Biking in Syracuse</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/mountain-biking-in-syracuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 12:26:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/mountain-biking-in-syracuse/</guid>
      <description>Today I went for Mountain Biking trip which is organized by SUOC. I&amp;rsquo;ve done mountain biking when I was in Indonesia almost every weekend. At first I was wondering where can I have good trails for mountain biking in Syracuse. The area is located near Syracuse University south campus. To give you better sense of direction, look at the map below.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t have a decent bike for mountain biking and never go for mountain biking with complete equipment but this time was different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canyoneering in Bear Swamp Creek</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/canyoneering-in-bear-swamp-creek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 07:06:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/canyoneering-in-bear-swamp-creek/</guid>
      <description>I just got home from my first canyoneering trip in my life. Thanks for Syracuse University Outing Club (SUOC) leaders who took me to this trip, here is the story. At first, we set off from SUOC Equipment room (E-room) at 10 am. There were seven people on this trip. Two leaders (Nate and Maggie) and five members (Nick, Megan, John, Sean and me). We went to Bear Swamp Creek in Cayuga County, New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First US&#39;s Family Home Visit</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-uss-family-home-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 06:26:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/my-first-uss-family-home-visit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, (4th of August 2013) we went on home visit. We were lucky to have Sue as our host family. Sue&amp;rsquo;s house is quite far from St. John&amp;rsquo;s University since it is located in Ringwood, New Jersey. We took a bus from New York Port Authority Bus Terminal (PABT) to Ringwood. I really enjoy our trip since along the road I saw beautiful trees. Unfortunately, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of trees was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakso Moro Seneng Pak Slamet Trenggalek</title>
      <link>http://www.riospace.web.id/bakso-moro-seneng-pak-slamet-trenggalek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 06:20:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.riospace.web.id/bakso-moro-seneng-pak-slamet-trenggalek/</guid>
      <description>Jika anda pecinta kuliner dan kebetulan sedang singgah di kota keripik Trenggalek pastikan anda menyempatkan diri mampir dan mencicipi Bakso Moro Seneng Pak Slamet.
Hiruk Pikuk pembeli sudah mulai ramai saat saya datang ke lokasi sekitar jam 10 pagi. Warung bakso yang terletak di Jalan Doktor Setiabudi dekat RSUD Doktor Soedomo Trenggalek ini memang selalu ramai pembeli. Usut punya usut ternyata yang menarik banyaknya pembeli ke warung tersebut adalah ke khas-an yang dimiliki oleh warung bakso tersebut yakni gorengan dan sambal baksonya.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>